For someone like myself, I've covered
tech my whole career.
3 and 1/2 million air miles, so many
times like in Taiwan, in Korea, you see
them building fabs 18 hours a day with
one bathroom break. Then I land in New
York Airport, there's a fist fight at
the Dunkin Donuts, and you wonder why
we're 17th in math.
Now, for the first time, US is ahead of
China when it comes to tech. You don't
want that to end. [music]
>> What's going on, guys? Today, we've got
Dan Ives on the podcast. Dan is the
partner and senior managing director at
Yorkville Ives, and he's here to talk
all about the AI trade. We talk about
the sectors that he's interested in, the
sectors where he thinks value's going to
accrue, and maybe some areas where you
should be cautious. We talk about the
private AI model labs, where is pressure
coming from, or is AI actually going to
kill us all, what happened at the White
House meeting, and then we even get into
what's going on with all of the personal
assistants that have been coming to the
market. Dan's got some very unique
thoughts on the AI trade, and I think
that if you watch this, it's going to
make you a smarter investor in the
market. And then Dan finally finishes
up, and he talks about the Ives Ultra
Fund. It's a brand new fund that he's
brought to market. It trades under the
ticker IVAI, and I think people are
going to be very interested to see how
they can hold a public stock and get
exposure to the leading private AI
companies. Here's my latest conversation
with Dan Ives.
All right, Dan. AI trade, obviously, was
super hot earlier this year, then got a
little cooling off in the summer, but it
feels like it's starting to come back
here a little bit. And we have the
private companies that are knocking on
the door of going public in Anthropic,
Open AI. But the public stocks, where do
you see value through the end of the
year? How how are you thinking about the
AI trade today?
>> Yeah. Look, I think the demand, I think
it started last quarter. That's where it
changed. Cuz the monetization you saw
specifically with Microsoft and the and
the other hyperscalers, I think that was
an inflection point quarter.
>> [snorts]
>> I think now a lot of it is on the
second, third, fourth derivatives. And
then, of course, memory stocks were
there. But I think you're seeing it
across infrastructure with Dell,
with Cisco. I think with cybersecurity
stocks, you're starting to see it play
out. Look, take a step back. We're less
than 15% through what the spending
trend's going to be the next 3 to 4
years. It's 4 to 5 trillion dollars.
For every dollar of CapEx, there's a $5
to $6 multiplier across the rest of
tech.
So, I think we're going to go through
these sort of ebbs and flows, the
regulatory capture, the Dalio essay. I
mean, some of these things will continue
to sort of get in the way to some extent
in the near term of the trade, but I
just continue to believe we are in the
early days of what's going to be a
multi-year tech bull market. The first
time in 30 years, US has added China
when it comes to tech.
>> When you see Dalio come out and
basically say, "Hey, we think that
there's a 5% chance or 10% chance of AI
killing us all. We must slow down." And,
you know, kind of all of these calls for
essentially like, "Hey, government,
regulate me harder."
I've never heard a business that is
serious talk this way. What's your
general read? Are they sincere in this?
Are they just trying to use it to slow
down their competitors so they can catch
up? Or or what's going on?
>> I mean, 1910, the guy who said, "We
can't go down this car route. We have to
stay horse and buggy. These cars kill
you."
I'm I'm just saying, the it's
technology. Technology always goes ahead
of regulatory. And, I think some of it
is I'll call regulatory capture. Like,
you go to the top floor and then you
pull the ladder up. Mhm. So, I think
there is some of that going on. And, I
think that's also why you had to have
that sort of all hands on meeting, you
know, with Trump at at the White House
because you have to get everyone on the
same page. Cuz the reality is going into
a midterm election cycle,
you know,
>> [clears throat]
>> talk like that, and me and you have
talked about this before. I think a lot
of the tech industry, they created the
PR nightmare, the black eye that now
they're contending with. But, it's it's
an arms race. And, if we slow down,
China accelerates. That's not a debate.
So, that's why every time I in terms of
like the politicians in the Beltway,
many, you know, do you want people that
are still using Blackberries and flip
phones to ultimately be the ones that
are, you know, the direction of
innovation in this country? And I think
that Look, it's not going to slow down.
And I think you saw how stocks reacted.
I think if you go back I go over the
weekend the bears that have called 10 of
the last two downturns. They're like,
"Oh, my cuz remember the bulls are
usually watching football hanging out
with their family." And the bears on
Saturday, that's usually where it peaks
out. But then the reality is is that you
you saw what Jensen talked about, what
Nadella talked about, what Karp talks
about in terms of sovereign AI. That's
more what I view as like a very sort of
middle-of-the-road view, and that's my
opinion. And this is not slowing down
anytime soon.
>> What I found interesting was, you know,
right after the call for the slowdown or
pacing or whatever the hell they were
saying, um Zuck came out and Zuck did
not talk about slowing down. Zuck talked
about, "Hey, it's our job to release
products that are safe." And my general
framework, but I want to hear if you
agree with this or not, is the companies
that are losing money, that have
negative cash flow, they're the ones
calling for the slowdown. The companies
that are profitable like the Facebooks,
the Googles, etc., I don't hear them
calling for a slowdown at all. And it
almost feels like depending on whether
you can fund this with non-dilutive
capital or not is ultimately determining
which side of the, you know, regulatory
capture argument you're on.
>> Yeah, so regulatory capture I agree on
the regulatory capture, but maybe at a
different angle. I view it as those
leading the F1 race, Anthropic, OpenAI,
you don't want others to catch up to
you. The way that that could ultimately
be called throwing sand in the gears.
>> you think that they're leading? Like
>> I don't even think there's a question
that they're I think I disagree.
>> All right, go ahead.
>> Good, good. It's good to disagree
>> All right, I want to hear about this.
>> When it comes to pure models and what
they're doing on the enterprise, I think
Anthropic and OpenAI have had the clear
lead. Do I believe that there's a gap
narrowing versus Meta versus Google
versus others? Yeah, because But you
see, I view it as the value chain is
going to be in the data. The models over
time will become more commoditized. So,
I don't become as focused on open-source
models as happen China. What Muse has
done is actually just a positive for
overall AI. So, I view it differently
rather than like the recent capital
component, I view it more like you're
way ahead in the race.
Others are starting to catch up. I could
argue like the Dario essay,
that was 20% of that added to Meta's
stock. Because Zuck looks at that and be
like, "Okay, you're going to go right
lane 55 miles, minivan, with a bumper
sticker saying
saying your kid was an honor student in
third grade.
I'll go in the left lane, Ferrari, and
we'll gain share." And that's
essentially what Zuck's done.
>> So,
I think that the private large lab
models are in way more trouble than
people realize. And I'll give you two uh
maybe examples.
First is my belief is that token
consumption leads revenue. So, if token
consumption starts ramping aggressively,
revenue follows.
I believe that the revenue has been
plateauing inside of these large
language models, Anthropic in
particular, mainly because the general
intelligence approach is not nearly as
valuable or large as people originally
thought. Because I think the original
thought process was you're going to
create the smartest model possible, and
then everyone is going to use it for
everything.
Now, what's happening though is people
are saying, "Wait a second, I want to
own my own intelligence."
>> Sa- Sa- sovereign AI.
>> I want to have applied AI for this
specific use case, and maybe I use them
to get started, because it's easy for me
to build some software, plug them in.
But if you take a Look at what we did
with Silvia.
We started off 100% as a chat GPT
wrapper. Over time we said well rather
than use chat GPT let's switch over to
Claude which seems to be better.
Our monthly compute expense went from
zero
to hundreds of thousands of dollars. We
were one of the fastest month over month
growing customers I think that Anthropic
had. Great, they loved us.
Then we said wait a minute, why are we
using from an architecture standpoint
model to do certain things? So there was
literally a point where you would
refresh the page on Silvia and you'd hit
the model. We're like let's stop doing
that, right? So you start to get smarter
about like when do we hit the model? How
do we hit the model? But then over time
it eventually became why don't we just
train our own models? Why don't we build
our own harness? Why don't we go and
actually have the sovereignty so we're
not having to use somebody else's
intelligence. We can also though make it
custom. So now we get better
performance, we get better accuracy, we
get lower cost and we get less latency.
So we're not going to give up on using
them. We'll still use them for plenty of
stuff. But the token consumption that
they have from us versus what we're
doing ourselves is shifting and so on
like a per customer basis it seems like
a lot of companies are saying hey I'm
not going to go to zero with them.
But actually I'm going to use them less
and less as I build my own stuff and to
me that feels like a massive headwind
that not a lot of people are talking
about.
>> So I think on some early adopt new adopt
look
sovereign AI and Karp talks about it
Jensen talks about it as well. Like that
that's the golden goose. It's about
companies now they've gotten their arms
around okay that data we ultimately want
to maintain and we don't want models
coming into that data to replicate our
business and ultimately put us out of
business.
I think the difference is that when you
look look 4% of companies have gone down
the AI path just in the US today.
>> Only 4%?
>> 4%.
>> Wow.
>> So that that's the difference on that.
So in other words if we were at 50% and
that can some I'd
>> So you think there's a lot of runway to
go. We're still in the zero to one phase
of just AI adoption in general. It's
only the people who are on kind of the
the frontier. They're the ones who are
starting to adopt sovereign AI, but that
might be 0.1% penetration.
>> No, and I and that's why so many CIOs
that I talked to, okay, the ones that
are very advanced, exactly where you are
and that's where like a sovereign AI,
you talk about like what Palantir,
Nvidia, some of the things even, you
know, I think some of the infrastructure
players are looking at.
But when you think like look, Europe,
they're building Blockbuster videos.
You know, you think about what's
happening India, they're trying to
figure out do they go US China, Middle
East very skewed toward US tech in terms
of what we've seen there. So it's a
two-horse race between the US and China.
When you think about why we're so
bullish, it's about the numbers. Europe,
eventually they're going to, you know,
once through the red tape, they'll
ultimately embrace AI. Middle East,
India, and then think about you're going
to get to another 60-70% of enterprises
that go after AI and adopt. That's still
on the come. And then think about on the
consumer side. That's just starting now
with Apple finally actually having AI.
You see what Meta's doing as well in
terms of Muse. So my view is like we
still have another two, three years of
just massive growth. And I think that's
something that investors are still
underestimating the scale and scope of.
>> Now, when you see uh all these leaders
come together in Washington D.C. They
meet with the president. Uh whether
people like him or not, one thing I
think everyone should agree on is that
he's good at branding. And he says his
artificial intelligence name sucks. I
want to name it super intelligence.
What are you going to call it?
>> Look, I mean, we still call it AI. So
I'm not But the point is like forget the
name thing.
Trump basically had to get everyone in a
room and be like, "Look, but like what's
going on?" And because you go into a
midterm election cycle, if you continue
to be dystopian,
talk negative, you know, about like what
this could do to mankind, guess what?
More data centers get shut down. It's
becoming a huge I think it's becoming a
huge debate no matter what the town,
what the state, what the city is.
It's very important that you get
everyone on the same page because every
data center that gets shut down, China
wins.
And that is I think the most important
part of where we are. You need more
self-regulation
rather than
public-private beltway talking points,
grandstanding type stuff because I think
that would be the most negative thing.
My whole view is like for someone like
myself who's covered tech my whole
career,
3 and 1/2 million air miles, so many
times like in Taiwan, in Korea, you see
them building fabs 18 hours a day with
one bathroom break.
Then I land in Newark Airport, there's a
fistfight at Dunkin' Donuts, and you
wonder why we're 17th in math.
Now for the first time, US is ahead of
China when it comes to tech. You don't
want that to end.
>> Today's episode is brought to you by
Arch Public. Arch Public has just
expanded its agentic trading platform
beyond crypto, so pay attention. This is
a big one. Now they are automating
strategies across stocks, commodities,
and ETFs, and I think that this is going
to be huge. You can now automatically
take profits when one market hits new
all-time highs and rotate that capital
into other markets showing more
opportunity. Whether you're rotating
capital into AI stocks, gold, if you're
investing in the S&P 500, or you're
accumulating Bitcoin, Arch Public brings
real discipline and automation to your
investment strategy. Additionally,
they've launched a powerful new tax loss
harvesting tool. With crypto being so
volatile and its exemption from the wash
sale rule, Arch Public can offset gains
with losses without compromising your
long-term positions. It's exactly what
every serious investor does.
Institutional grade automation that
works across every major asset class.
There's no more emotional trading, no
more missing tax opportunities, just
smarter, hands-free execution of your
preferred strategies. Go to
archpublic.com
right now. Connect with their team, set
up a time, bring your account, and if
you'd like, then you can learn what
automated trading can do for you.
archpublic.com
>> Do you worry about
America pursuing a closed source model
versus China pursuing a open weight open
source model, or do you think that
actually American open source needs to
become much more prevalent?
>> think that's what Nvidia has done. I
mean, you go out to the hugging
acquisition. I mean, that cuz Jensen
understands
better than anyone. Forget it, like
>> He He does feel like the biggest adult
in the room by far.
>> It's not even a question. He is the
adult in the I actually think the two
that understand it the most are Jensen
and Karp.
>> Interesting.
>> Because they understand just forget the
model cuz everyone focus on the models
and
they have a much more, I think, global
view because of I think in terms of
Palantir where they ultimately work with
in terms of enterprise, but specifically
government. I think Jensen has the most
global view. Jensen understands open
source you need
just based on cost. Think about it.
Let's say phones, going back 2007, 2008.
Let's say Apple priced the phones double
where they were in 2007, 2008. Would you
have 1.5 billion iPhones today? No.
You have to make sure a tokenization
cost, the pricing, open source. That's
why I think Muse also, just as a as a
side note, is very important. And that's
why, like, I think the most important
person that has the best perspective is
Nvidia, and he continues to sort of be
the calming force. Even when you did the
all-in podcast, you know, right after
the Dario essay sub opera on the
weekend, and that was like such an
important time for the market.
>> Well, so this goes back to these large
language models, right? I think everyone
now has seen this chart where all of the
token prices they're pushing out on the
frontier in terms of their intelligence,
but they're coming down in price. And so
you have this essentially a price war
occurring. So, if you go back to well,
what is the revenue of a model app? It
is token price times token consumption
equals revenue. So, if you have
consumption per customer dropping, and
you have token price dropping, it just
feels like there's massive pressure. So,
then the question becomes Anthropic was
supposed to go public this year. OpenAI
was and then came out and said they're
not going to. Do you think we get the
Anthropic IPO before the end of the
year?
>> Yeah, I think. I mean, I think that's
like I'd be shocked if that doesn't
happen.
>> Mhm.
>> And then
>> Well, we've seen
uh take Oura Ring. Those guys, they
claim they were 4x oversubscribed. They
claim, you know, all of these great
metrics going into the IPO, and then the
night of uh the night before they
basically pull it. I don't know what
happened there, right? But it does feel
like and they blamed, by the way, market
conditions, which is kind of like a
nonsense thing, right? But fine.
>> I couldn't get to the dinner cuz of
traffic.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> We should definitely do it again.
>> [laughter]
>> So, uh do you feel like Anthropic, same
thing, is like maybe it's not an
Anthropic problem, but they just say
look at the market and say there's too
much here going into a midterm, let's
not let's not go out.
>> I just think after the mid after the
midterm it happen. Look, to me, it's one
First, I think also like when it comes
like public, it's always hard to compare
cuz be like this IPO got pushed or that
Anthropic is a is a whole different
game. Just because globally, and I think
we saw this with SpaceX as well, the
appetite to understand what the
trajectory looks like, they'll look do
they have unique risk factors? Like
mankind, you You of course.
But I do think we're going into a golden
age for AI. We're going into a golden
age where many of the private companies
ultimately will be public.
And I think that's healthy. Because for
the overall tech trade, Anthropic and
OpenAI being public is good. It's not
bad. I think it actually
and I think that's ultimately where it's
going. SpaceX, OpenAI, Anthropic being
public are are actually very good for
the market.
>> I agree. I just think that
when I talk with people, there is this
blind belief, these are amazing
companies. And when I push on,
specifically people who aren't like
analyst, why do you think they're a good
company? They start talking about the
quality of the product. And maybe my
word of caution to people is just like a
good product does not equal a good
company.
You can have a good product and a good
One It is undeniable the products are
amazing. People love using them.
But when you start to hear some of the
data points that are coming out, you
know, in terms of what's in the uh the
S-1, you look at some of the the uh kind
of trends,
I just think there's way more headwind
than uh than maybe people think because
you're dealing with a
you're dealing with an industry where
look at Jev, right? Maybe as as a good
example.
Like that wasn't on the chessboard 3
weeks ago.
>> Mhm.
>> All of a sudden, zero to $100 million
run rate in you know, the first week and
scaling.
And I use our engineering team as a
uh maybe a a pressure point for me. So,
I go ask them, I say, "Hey, how many of
our queries are routing through various
models?"
All of a sudden, Jev now, it's not 50%
but they're starting to use it. And
they're starting to put it in places
where previously you couldn't use one of
the frontier models cuz it was cost
prohibitive.
And so, you start to almost like it's
like death by 1,000 cuts it feels like.
And we're going to get this huge
fragmentation,
which maybe to your point, that's why
they're trying to pull the ladder up, is
because that would solidify them as the
centralized winner.
>> Well, also, Anthropic and OpenAI,
they've been very intelligent and smart
seeing around the corner, building up
the enterprise sales force.
>> Mhm.
>> Going after come cuz they recognize that
been pretty early on like the consumer
piece is not where they're going to
monetize. They're going to monetize on
the enterprise. But then it goes back to
like listen 5% of companies have gone
down the AI path.
Take a company just given the amount of
data they ingest, they start to go to
AI, what that's going to do from an
incremental business perspective for
Anthropic, for open AI, but for the
overall industry, it speaks to
>> Well, even meta, right? News for small
business. They're all, you know, going
that way.
>> And that's a good example like with meta
like everyone counted them out. They're
spending like 19 years rock stars.
You're not seeing the actual, you know,
return.
When you have 3 and 1/2 billion users,
you could be late. They
look at it now what time of the stock.
Apple same thing, right? Apple bear set
stocks it should be like 200 to fit
They don't get it because
it's about the install base. 1.5 billion
iPhones, 2.5 billion iOS devices. You're
now a toll collector on the consumer AI
highway. I just think whether you're
bullish on Anthropic or bearish or open
AI
take a step back. This AI trade is
spreading.
>> Mhm.
>> Not just from memory to infrastructure
to a lot of even the traditional
players, the HPs, the Dells, the Cisco
it's going to go to energy. It's going
to go to infrastructure. And I think
that is a very key theme and I just
think a lot of investors that you know,
have missed really every
transformational growth stock the last
25 years
it's very I think it's a
it's a part of the market where you have
to be able to look out 2 3 years.
Physical AI
globally what I believe is it going to
be US tech dominance and what that means
for innovation this country, and I just
continue also believe
the taking jobs away narrative,
just like the SaaS apocalypse,
I think was way, way overdone. And I
think now you're starting to see some of
that play out. More jobs will be created
by AI than taken away over the next
decade in my view.
>> Easy. And look, we see this
inside of our company, there are more
agents than humans.
There are jobs that we did not go hire
for because the agents can do it. But,
because the agents are so productive,
the company is growing faster than it
would otherwise, which then leads to us
being able to hire more people.
>> And innovation in this country, it used
to be like, if you wanted to do a
startup, you got to get seed funding
this 20 million, 30. Now, because of the
engineering horsepower that you could
do, think about the innovation that now
could happen in this country. And I just
think it's a
it goes back to like the White House
meeting and big tech and where we are.
Everyone recognized like this is a
moment in time.
And it is just very important that you
do not put the brakes on. You put the
brakes on, we will look back
5, 10 years from now be like, how did
China get so ahead of us? And I think
it's just it's a very, very
sensitive,
like whatever you call it, like hot
button topic, but I don't really see any
gray in terms of the direction that we
have to go.
>> So, let's say I'm an investor. I'm
looking at the entire public markets,
and I'm saying to myself, all right,
there's a lot here to unpack. I've got
the mag seven, I've got the
infrastructure, I've got all the data
centers, I've got memory, I've got, you
know, pure play AI.
How do I think through allocating money?
Right? Is it
put a certain percentage of my portfolio
in AI overall, or these like different
sectors, but like the entire economy now
is AI, and so of course you've got to,
you know, have it throughout your
portfolio? Just like, how are you
talking to me about this?
>> It's about second, third, fourth
derivatives. Like I I continue to
believe large cap tech is starting like
flex its muscles again. You look like
Nvidia is a good example. Like those
that continue to sort of
you know, defy or that they think it's
getting tired, it's not a shiny new
object anymore. You could argue that
that stock is way cheaper today than it
was 6 to 12 months ago, and you still
haven't even gone into what's going to
be the full wave of physical AI and and
where we're playing.
Our Asia check showed 13 to 1 demand.
I demand and supply 13 to 1 for chips in
Asia. That's also why like AMD. Count if
you look like what Lisa Su's done,
they're just starting in terms on the
chip side. I just think you have to own
chips. You got to own the hyperscalers,
and I think you've seen specifically
Microsoft, Amazon, Google like
reinserting themselves because of the
install base, and it goes back to like
less than 5% that have gone down the AI
path as more head down that path. That's
bullish for the hyperscalers. The
software, the SaaS apocalypse, I think
it was a fictional narrative, and I
think there's a lot of these if you look
like from Salesforce to ServiceNow. Of
course, Palantir weeding in, and I think
that's one that's almost going to become
a category changer, especially as the
free cash flow ramps significantly.
Cybersecurity, another example. Go back
to like April.
Cybersecurity is done. Anthropic's
eating their lunch. Look at CrowdStrike,
Palo Alto, Zscaler. Look at those
stocks. Now look at it.
And then I think you have to even go
further out and look like infrastructure
and energy. My whole point is from an
allocation perspective, you own the core
names and winners and themes,
but then you have to see where
everything is heading. Like when when
when like look at Tesla. Like when are
they actually going to start to now
transition from that EV player to
ultimately robotaxis, autonomous,
optimist. Once the transition happened,
you've already missed it.
>> Mhm.
Personal agents are all the rage now.
You've got, you know, the Grok boxes of
the world who are kind of sort of
personal agents, but then you've got
Instinct, Muse, etc. How does that
impact the AI market? And
[clears throat] those are consumer. It
seems like these businesses, at least
Instinct and Zoc have both come out and
said that they are not going to try to
charge the consumer. They're going to
find other ways to monetize.
>> Yeah.
>> What do you just think about that as a
sector and and how investors should
think about it?
>> that's going to be like a whole 'nother
area of investing. Because my whole
point is like you have to think about
like the enterprise, then the consumer
piece. Clearly like the infrastructure,
if it was the gold rush, there was the
picks and shovels, like they're
ultimately going to benefit on either
side. But if you think about on the
consumer, we're just now starting the
consumer ad revolution. That's why I
think
Apple, the stock's doing what it's
doing. And I think you start to see what
I believe is going to almost be like a
new category that comes on the line.
We're going to be talking about stocks
18 24 months from now
that we we don't we're not talking about
today.
>> Mhm.
>> But that's why it goes back to my view
like you don't have equilibrium
till late 2028, early 2029 in terms of
chips.
And I think that's something despite
like 10-year
oil, geopolitical, whatever the moment
and the sort of, you know, the
nervousness of the time, I think tech is
going to continue to plow through and be
the leader of this market.
>> interesting because the macro
environment, almost everything is
telling you, "Hey, top or headwinds,
right?" You have interest rates going
up, you have oil, you know, 100 bucks or
so, you've got 10-year over 5%, uh
people are very nervous, uh home prices
are, you know, quote-unquote falling.
All this stuff that if I wanted to paint
you a very
>> K-shaped economy.
>> Yeah, well, if I wanted to paint you a
just a very negative story, I could do
it easily.
>> But if I told you 6 months ago, we're
sitting here I know a new studio and
that, but like before the new studio,
and I said 6 months from now,
oil 105 110,
10-year 5.2 5.3,
Iran still going as I told you
everything and I said, "Okay,
where do you think S&P and Nasdaq are?"
You probably would be off by 15% lower.
>> Mhm.
I agree with that.
>> Because it comes down the market is
telling you
we're in a fourth industrial revolution.
The growth, I could argue the 10-year is
there because of the growth and because
we're going to be ultimately more and
more debt raises and because of the data
center build out and because of what
we're seeing it from a CapEx
perspective.
So, I just think investors, you can
my whole career going back to the '80s,
if I got caught up in like geopolitical,
Europe's going bankrupt, they
Dude, about my mind is like I my career
would not be where it is today. So, I'm
just saying it's very easy to get caught
up in the bears, the catastrophists
that have called 10 of the last two
downturns to scare retail. And I think
that always creates the opportunities.
>> Mhm.
>> This episode is brought to you by Lava.
The Lava Card is the first credit card
that allows you to earn up to 5% back in
Bitcoin on every single purchase. Most
cards have steep annual fees and unclear
points programs, but the Lava Card
offers a much better deal. Earn real
Bitcoin every time that you spend. Plus,
there's no annual fee. There's zero FX
fees and zero spread when you spend
internationally. On top of that, Lava
gives you access to a Bitcoin line of
credit, yield on cash, instant
stablecoin deposits and withdrawals, on
and off-ramps to and from your bank
account, and much, much more.
With Lava, you can borrow against your
Bitcoin at the lowest rates, earn yield,
move money globally, and stack Bitcoin
with each and every purchase you make.
Most financial services squeeze you with
high fees, confusing rewards programs.
Lava keeps it simple and they help you
build your long-term savings via your
everyday spend. Visit lava.xyz/pomp
to get started in just a few minutes
today. lava.xyz/pomp
to get started today.
99% of Warren Buffett's wealth was
accumulated after his 50th birthday.
>> [music]
>> The asset that made that possible was
not in his portfolio though. It was his
health. The first rule of investing is
you actually got to be around to
compound. Investor Health is a platform
that we recently created and I want you
to go test it to tell us what you think.
Investor Health is for people who take
their body as seriously as their
portfolio. Weight, [music] metabolism,
energy, longevity, GLP-1s, NAD+, B12,
all prescribed by licensed clinicians.
Here's how it works. You complete a
short online form. A board-certified
clinician reviews it and decides what's
right for you. Your medication is
compounded and shipped to your door and
most patients in 48 to 72 hours receive
it. No office visits, no referrals, no
waiting rooms. Programs start at $149 a
month. It's about $5 a day and it's HSA
and FSA eligible. No contracts, [music]
cancel anytime and it's available in all
50 states. Go to investorhealth.com to
learn more and go long on life. You got
to be around to compound.
investorhealth.com [music]
Investor Health is a telehealth
platform, not a medical provider.
Medical services are provided by
affiliated licensed clinicians.
Compounded medications are not FDA
approved.
>> [music]
>> Individual results may vary and
treatment requires evaluation by a
licensed provider. Terms and conditions
apply. See investorhealth.com [music]
You recently priced a brand new
financial product uh in the market.
It is a special purpose investment fund,
which is kind of like a SPAC, but it's
an investment fund. $200 million raised.
And my understanding is that you're
going to take this, which is called the
AIV Ultra Fund.
You're going to the ticker is IVAI.
You're going to take it and go invest in
the private market. So, it's a publicly
traded permanent capital vehicle that
will have exposure to private companies.
What are you going to look for to to
allocate capital?
>> And it's the first public company ever
to invest in private AI tech companies.
Look, for me, so many people around the
world, whether it's retail, financial
advisors, well, whoever it may be,
someone in an airport, how do you invest
in private tech companies? Institutions
is the big issue, right? There's SPDs,
SPV2, SPV3.
>> Boy, stop at three.
>> [laughter]
>> You can go to My whole view is to create
a vehicle that you could own the leading
private tech companies and give, instead
of just a small club outside Silicon
Valley that can own them. Why can't
people in the public own these private
tech companies? And that's what we're
doing. I mean, it's going to, you know,
this is really kind of a Swiss Army
knife approach to try and identify what
that portfolio looks like, whether it's
some of them are bigger players or
well-known today to some that like, who
could be the next Palantir?
>> Mhm.
>> Who could be the next model
that that ultimately drives this market?
And that was really the origin doing it
with partners Ed and Jeff Leather.
It Look, it was super exciting to do
that because I just believe it's a new
frontier.
>> Mhm. I think it's a very good idea.
Um, and also I think that you are the
right person to go and find these
private AI companies. And the blending
of the public and private markets
continues, right? Whether it's
tokenization, whether it's funds like
this. Like we have seen this play out,
and this just feels like another step in
that direction.
>> Well, it's like why if someone's like
you're in a private credit fund,
why can you be in a private tech product
where you own private AI tech? Look, it
comes down to like this is the new
landscape.
The reality is trillions of dollars are
going to be spent in this sector. A lot
of it's going to be spent by private
company on private companies that are
leading it. And trying to identify that
and I think if you go back historically,
it was a small group of people or
companies that could buy these comp-
that could buy these private
companies. And I think it's just
important where we are today to create a
public vehicle
that does that.
>> Yeah. It it's very very interesting also
to see the private companies how fast
they're growing. Like one of the
companies I'm an investor in is called
MicroOne. And MicroOne is
a data business, but the data business
is, you know, Scale AI's like a data
labeling business. These guys have some
data labeling to them, but also they are
going out and they're paying doctors and
lawyers, etc. to go and actually create
data for them to then go and sell
through. They're now going to companies
and they'll pay pretty large amounts of
it. Um and I'll give you one that I'd
never heard of before. Somebody emailed
me this week and said, "Hey, will you
license us the podcast?"
Because they want the data.
I don't know if we're going to do it. I
have no clue what that even means. We
haven't talked to them yet, whatever,
but I was just like,
"Oh,
data is data." Like there's going to be
data all over the place that people are
going to try to buy up and use for all
these different
>> Data is the new oil and gold. Like why
do you think Amazon put the gates up
with Muse?
Because the reality is that
and that's why sovereign AI is such an
important dynamic, which you could say
is negative for the mono players, cuz
companies say, "Okay, we want to have
control of our data. We're going to do
it in our walls and I think that's
See,
different than the model players that
are narrowing the gap, I actually think
sovereign AI is more of the bigger
debate.
>> Why?
>> Because
companies are starting to get their sea
legs. They're starting to understand
like, okay, we got to go full AI. We
need these strategic paths, but is it
just giving it an out sourcing it to and
then I think
>> like there's no way that's going to
happen.
>> So that's So that's So it could you go
through evolutions, right? Like
it's no different than
any technology.
The technology
it's going to take time for these
companies to recognize like trial and
error, what's the best path.
And I just think like that's going to
create so many more opportunities
for other companies to monetize.
>> I don't think people understand the
sovereign AI thing, right? It's own your
own intelligence sovereign AI, however
you want to call it.
Again, I just know the thing that we
have seen. If we route a model or a
query to our models on our hardware
versus go to the frontier models, the
cost savings is about 97%.
But the cost is not the reason to do it
exclusively.
It's actually the answers are more
accurate. So what I always go back to
and and to be honest, the first when we
first started going down this path, we
had some very smart AI engineers and
they were explaining to me what they
thought was possible and all that stuff.
And you kind of have in the back of your
head, dude, there's no way
a team of six, seven, eight engineers is
going to beat a trillion dollar company.
And then they explained to me, well, let
me show you how this works. And so today
we've come out and we've showed Silvia
is more accurate on tax, mortgage,
credit cards, you know, these personal
finance topics.
But it is less about how many engineers
you have or anything. It's are you
general or are you, you know, applied
AI? And then what is the data set that
you're able to use to get to that level
of accuracy, the the
reinforcement learning, all of the eval
rubrics, like all of these components.
And I just started to realize I was
like,
if we can pull this off,
dude, what is it going to happen when
these large companies start realizing,
why don't we just do it ourselves?
And they have hundreds, thousands of
engineers. Like this is going to
completely change the way that people
think about this technology being
integrated into these companies.
>> But is it democratization of the
technology? See, I I don't view it as a
See, I view it as
>> It's empowering for the company.
>> This is not just a duopoly.
>> Mhm.
>> If it was a Let's just say this was just
OpenAI and Anthropic.
And Nvidia was selling the chips.
Like that as a bull case in this market,
that's not
You need democratiz- You need data
sovereignty. And I actually think like
this is actually like, like I said, it's
third inning
of this game. Because it's not Those
that say, "Oh, it's sixth, seventh
inning."
I mean,
I go around the country so much like
looking at the data centers and I just
think even if 10 to 15% get voted down,
like you're going to have 800,000 data
centers built in the next 12, 18 months.
Like
that is that's building the hearts and
lungs of what's going to be
really a new economy that's building out
in this in this country.
>> It's 100% a new economy. And And I think
that
I'll leave you with this. I recently was
talking with some of the engineers and
and I said to them I said, "Would it be
offensive if I told you that I'm I've
now retrained myself over the last 6
months and I'm a software engineer?"
My entire career I've been, you know, I
was product manager at Facebook and like
understand product. I would never
writing code, right? Even if, you know,
I was building a WordPress site. It was
kind of like you're hacking it together.
I'm not a software engineer. I don't
have a computer science degree, all this
kind of stuff. And for people who are
non-technical who work with engineers,
there's kind of like a bright line.
>> Yes.
>> You you you do not claim to do what they
do because they are very special. They
They're the stars, you're the support
staff, right? It's kind of the way I've
always thought about it.
But I said to him, I said, "Look,
here's [snorts] how I have started to
think about this." And And one of the
engineers, right, one of our best
engineers said to me, "If I was doing an
interview to hire a software engineer,
one of the first questions I ask is show
me what you've built."
And he's like, "And you have all this
stuff that you've built." So, he's like,
"The lines are blurring." Now, I'm not
going to go actually put software
engineer on my Twitter bio, right? You
know, like bang my chest and be like,
"I'm a software engineer now." But, if
that starts to become a skill that dummy
me can use,
what happens when that permeates
throughout society and throughout the
economy and now all of a sudden
productivity accelerates?
>> But that's the whole the whole point
that the Fed's talked about is that
>> Yeah.
>> new technology the last 100 years has
been a net job detractor or it's about
productivity enhanced. And I just think
sometimes as you're going through the
storm, the turbulence, you can't see the
other side.
Sometimes I think it's very easy to get
caught up in narratives in this market.
And I think that's some of the dangers
as an investor, too, when you get too
caught up because you cuz I see it from
an end user. I see it from CIO. I see it
in Asia. I see it from a chip brick.
When you see the innovate, you see
physical AI that's ultimately coming.
And that's why like when you have adults
in the room like Jensen kind of
navigating it, I think that you just
continue sort That's the yellow brick
road to the success.
>> Yeah, it's fascinating. Where can
someone go to find you online?
>> Yeah, so dives tech. And again, I don't
block hardly anyone or or or LinkedIn.
And No, look, I appreciate Look, this is
just it's an important time to sort of,
you know, navigate the narratives in
some of these white-knuckle moments and
make sure investors just don't get, you
know, sort of caught up sometimes in the
in the in these battles from the
hibernation mode.
>> I think you're doing a great job. I'm
very excited about
>> No, thank you so much.
>> IVAI is is the ticker and we'll do this
again. I'm going to convince you to
start doing this weekly.
>> Hey,
I'm I'm here for it.
>> [laughter]
>> All right, we'll see everyone soon.
>> Thanks.